嘿
Hey.
想什么呢
Where'd you go?
没什么
I'm here.
伙计们
Um, guys.
其实...
So...
那谷仓里全是行尸
The barn is full of walkers.
你可别告诉我这没什么大不了的
You cannot tell me you're all right with this.
当然不是  但我们是客
No I'm not, but we're guests here.
这里不是我们的地盘
This isn't our land.
-但命是我们自己的  -小声点
- This is our lives! - Lower your voice.
我们不能就这么算了
We can't just sweep this under the rug.
这肯定不行  绝对不行
It ain't right. Not remotely.
好吧  我们要么冲进去
Okay, we've either got to go in there,
把他们搞定  要么掉脸走人
We've got to make things right or we've just got to go.
去本宁堡的路线我们已经讨论够久了
Now we have been talking about Fort Benning for a long time.
我们不能走
We can't go.
为什么  瑞克  为什么
Why, rick? Why?
因为我女儿还没找到
Because my daughter is still out there.
好吧
Okay.
我觉得现在我们也该
Okay, I think it's time that we all start to just
-考虑下另一种可能了吧  -肖恩
-consider the other possibility.  - Shane
我们不能扔下索菲亚不管
We're not leaving Sophia behind.
我差一点就找到那孩子了
I'm close to finding this girl.
两天前我还找到了她的娃娃
I just found her damn doll two days ago.
你找到了她的娃娃  达里尔
You found her doll, Daryl.
可不是嘛  只个娃娃而已
That's what you did. You found a doll.
你他妈根本不知道自己在说什么
You don't know what the hell you're talking about.
我只是说句实话
I'm just saying what needs to be said.
只有在失踪前48小时找到的线索
You get a good lead,
才能算得上好线索
it's in the first 48 hours.
肖恩  别说了
Shane, stop.
我跟你直说了吧  伙计
Let me tell you something else, man.
就算她还活着
If she was alive out there
看到你疯疯癫癫地走过来  手拿猎刀
and saw you coming all methed out with your buck knife
脖子上还挂了串僵尸耳朵
and geek ears around your neck,
她也会被吓得朝另一个方向跑
she would run in the other direction.
-后退  -别碰我
- Back off! - Keep your hands off me.
让我跟赫谢尔谈谈
Now just let me talk to hershel.
-让我来解决  -你要怎么解决
- Let me figure it out. - What are you gonna figure out?!
如果我们想留下来 想清掉这个谷仓
If we're gonna stay, if we're gonna clear this barn,
我得先说服他  这是他的地盘
I have to talk him into it. This is his land.
赫谢尔把这些行尸看作人
Hershel sees those things in there as people--
病人
Sick people--
他的妻子  他的继子
his wife, his stepson.
你知道这事
You knew?
我昨天刚跟赫谢尔谈过
Yesterday I talked to Hershel.
那你还瞒了我们一晚上
And you waited the night?
我觉得我们还能安全地过上一晚
I thought we could survive one more night.
事实的确如此
We did.
我本想今早再说的
I was waiting till this morning to say something.
但格伦想亲自告诉大家
But glenn wanted to be the one.
那人是个疯子  瑞克
The man is crazy, rick,
如果赫谢尔认为那些行尸还活着
If hershel thinks those things are alive.
住嘴
No.
《行尸走肉》
玛姬
Maggie.
玛姬  别不理我啊
Hey, maggie, just talk to me.
喂
Hey.
玛姬
Maggie.
把帽子给我
Give me your hat.
你说想谈谈  那就谈呐
You said talk to you, I'm talking to you.
把帽子给我
Give me your hat.
你干嘛要这样浪费鸡蛋
Why would you waste an egg like that?
我觉得这鸡蛋坏了
I think it was rotten.
肖恩觉得索菲亚死了吗
Does shane think sophia's dead?
他只是害怕了而已
Shane's just scared.
-怕谷仓里的行尸?  -是的
- of the walkers in the barn? - Yeah.
妈
Mom,
在找到索菲亚之前  我是不会走的
I'm not leaving until we find sophia.
而且  找到之后我也不想离开
And I don't want to go even after that.
我们不会离开的  卡尔
Well, we're not leaving, carl.
你把作业写完吧
You finish those problems.
我只是觉得
I just think...she...
她会喜欢这里的
She's gonna like it here.
这里  这里就像家一样
This place, it could be a home.
-你不能这样  -我没事
- You can't. - I'm fine.
赫谢尔说你需要多休息
Hershel said you need to heal.
是吗  我不在乎
Yeah, I don't care.
可我在乎
Well, I do.
瑞克待会要出去接着找
Rick's going out later to follow the trail.
是吗  我也不会袖手旁观的
Yeah well, I ain't gonna sit around and do nothing.
不行  你去会伤得更重
No, you're gonna go out there and get yourself hurt even worse.
不知道还能不能找到她  达里尔
We don't know if we're gonna find her, daryl.
不确定
We don't.
我不确定
I don't.
什么
What?
我不能再失去你
Can't lose you too.
-你没事吧  -别管我
- Are you all right? - Just leave me be.
蠢女人
Stupid bitch.
安德莉亚在找你
Andrea's looking for you.
谢谢  格伦
Thank you, Glenn.
你能再找顶帽子吗
Any chance you got an extra hat?
找不到了
Nope.
谢了
Thanks.
我要跟瑞克一起去找索菲亚
Going off with Rick to look for Sophia.
我以为他在跟赫谢尔谈呢
I thought he was talking with Hershel.
他去谈了  我们准备等他谈完了再去
He is. We're gonna go after.
我现在要去谷仓
I'm headed to the barn in the meantime.
肖恩说要个人在那守着
Shane wants a watch duty down there.
瑞克知道吗
Does Rick?
当然
Why wouldn't he?
你只拿你的枪吗
Are you only getting yours?
我不知道你和他之间发生什么了
I don't know what's going on with you and him.
-谁  -肖恩
- Him? - Shane.
-戴尔  -这不关我事
- Dale. - It's not my business.
我只是担心你...
All that matters to me is that you--
你也许并不了解他
You may not really know him.
我们之间不需要这样的
We don't need to do this.
-你跟我终于...  -这很重要
- You and I are finally-- - it's important.
我知道  你不喜欢他
I get it. You don't like him.
-不是这样  -那是什么
- It isn't that. - Then what is it?
你想那么过日子吗
Is that how you want to be?
像他那样
Like him?
他不是受害者
He's not a victim.
你不了解他
You don't know him.
戴尔  我希望你别再这样了
Dale, I need you to stop.
你花这么多精力
You spend so much time
照顾我  守着我
Watching me, looking out for me.
我只要一关心你  你就开始训我
You want to beat me up anytime I show any concern.
你走吧  我不说了
Go ahead. I'm done.
我不是要训你  戴尔
I'm not beating you up, Dale.
我没事  真的  情况已经...
I'm okay, really. Things are...
不同了
different.
我看你该出发了
You got your gun.
好吧
Okay.
-你还好吧  -没事
- You okay? - Yeah.
跑一趟帮我拿点水来行吗
You mind running and getting me some water?
我...
I just--
我想休息会儿
I need a second.
你接着守吗
You'll keep watch?
戴尔
Dale?
是的  没问题
Yeah sure.
请进
Come on in.
吃饭还看书啊
A little light reading for lunch?
我最近很努力
Been working so hard lately
无论在哪都要接着研究
I get my studying where I can.
你知道我们可以帮你的
You know we can help you out with your work.
这属于我研究的范畴
It's my field to tend.
我们知道了谷仓的事
We found the barn.
别管它
Leave it be.
我想和你谈谈这件事
Well, I'd like to talk about it,
不过
but either way--
无论是谷仓还是农场还是你说了算
your barn, your farm, your say.
我不想和你谈谷仓的事
I don't want to talk about the barn.
我也不想和你争论
I don't want to debate.
不是争论  是讨论
Not a debate, a discussion.
你和你的人周末之前得离开这
I need you and your group gone by the end of the week.
我和戴尔谈过了
I talked to Dale.
在行尸的问题上
You and I have our differences
我们看法不同
with the way we look at the walkers.
那些人
Those people,
他们也许已经死了  也许还活着
they may be dead, they may be alive.
但是我们这些人
But my people, us,
我们现在还活着
we are alive right now,
就在这  就在你眼前
right here, right in front of you.
你要是逼我们离开  有些人可能就活不成了
You send us out there and that could change.
我给你们提供了避风港
I've given you safe harbor.
我对得起自己的良心
My conscience is clear.
这个农场
This farm--
这个农场很特殊
this farm is special.
你们早已与世隔绝
You've been shielded from what's been going on out there.
戴尔说你在新闻上看到了发生的一切
Dale said you saw everything happen on the news.
但新闻已经很久没播了
Well, it's been-- it's been a long time since the cameras stopped rolling.
我第一次见到行尸的时候
The first time I saw a walker,
它只有半个身子  想要咬我
it was just half a body snapping at me from the ground.
我也不想杀它
My inclination wasn't to kill it.
但现在外面的世界
But what the world is out there
和你在电视上看到的不一样了
isn't what you saw on TV.
变得非常糟糕  足以改变一个人
It is much much worse and it changes you.
不管是变成行尸
Either into one of them
还是变得比以前野蛮
or something a lot less than the person you were.
请不要逼我们离开
Please do not-- do not send us out there again.
我妻子怀孕了
My wife's pregnant.
在这里  这是件高兴的事
That's either a gift here
一出去  就是必死无疑
or a death sentence out there.
如果你让我们留在这
If we were to stay we could help you
我们可以帮你干活  保卫这个地方
with the work, with securing this place.
我们可以一起活下去
We can survive together.
瑞克  我说了不行
Rick, I'm telling you we can't.
-你想想自己在做什么  -我想过了
- You think about what you're doing. - I've thought about it.
-仔细想想  -我想过了
- Think about it. - I've thought about it.
那就再仔细想想  我们不能离开这
Think about it again. We can't go out there.
怎么样  老兄
What's it gonna be, man?
我们留还是走
Which way does this thing go?
我还不知道
I don't know yet.
他怎么说
Well, what did he say?
-我们还在商量  -你们商...
- We're negotiating. - You're nego--
时间紧迫  瑞克
Clock's ticking, Rick.
不是的  肖恩
No it isn't, Shane.
谷仓很安全
That barn-- the barn is secure.
要不是听他说  我们根本发现发了
We didn't even know about it till this morning.
我们是没发现  但是现在知道了
We didn't. Well, we know about it now.
我们现在知道那里面有一群行尸
Right? We know there's over a dozen walkers in there.
谷仓离我们的营地只有一步之遥
We know that it's about a stone's throw
我们就睡在谷仓周围
from our camp, Rick-- where we sleep.
所以  如果不进去把它们杀了
So look, if we're not gonna go
我们还是赶紧离开为好
in there and clear it out then we just got to go.
我们不能杀死它们  也不能离开
We're not gonna clear it out and we're not gonna go.
我们至少得配枪防身
We at least need our guns.
我们不能用枪  在这不行
We can't have them, not here.
这个地方这么不安全
Why do you want to stay here
你为什么还要留在这
when it's not safe?
我们可以让这变安全
We can make it safe.
-怎么做  -我们会的
- How we gonna do that? - We will, okay?
怎么能让这个地方变安全
How we gonna make it safe?
我们会的  好吗
We will, okay?
不  老兄  这不行
No, man, it's not okay.
肖恩  洛莉怀孕了
Shane, Lori's pregnant.
我们需要留在这
We need to stay.
我们需要枪
We need our guns.
不需要  我会处理好的
No, I can work this out.
-你没事吧  -没事
- You good? - Yeah.
洛莉有小宝宝了  老兄
Lori's having a baby, man.
恭喜
Congratulations.
谢谢
Thank you.
嗨  亲爱的
Hi, honey.
卡尔不需要我的照看了
Carl doesn't need any more of my help.
那就是这样了吗
So that's it?
瑞克想要说服我
Rick was trying to make his case.
虽然离开这后会很难  要时刻小心
It'll be hard. They'll have to be careful.
但他的表现一直让人印象深刻
But he was being dramatic.
他们是强有力的队伍  一路上做得都很好
They're a strong group. They've done well on their own.
他们只是要离开这  去寻找自己的农场
They're just gonna have to go out and find their own farm.
现在外面有大把的选择
There's plenty of them now to chose from.
没有的  这些农场不是被烧了
There aren't. Every one of them nearby
就是挤满了行尸
is burned out or full of walkers.
行尸
Walkers?
那难道我们让这些人永远留在这吗
So we just keep these people here forever?
我要如何承担责任
How are they my responsibility?
给你个建议
A new command I give to you:
像我爱你那样  去爱别人
Love one another as I have loved you.
这是你告诉我的  不是吗
That's what you told me, right?
我曾经很生继母的气
I was mad about mom.
气你娶了安妮特
Mad about you marrying Annette.
我只有14岁  对你
I was 14 years old and I was awful,
比对别人更糟糕
to you more than anybody.
我只想吸烟  偷商店里的东西
All I wanted to do was smoke and shoplift.
去爱别人  你当时告诉我的
Love one another. That's what you told me.
玛姬
Maggie.
这不一样
That was different.
不
No.
是你不一样了
You're different.
我是不一样了
I am.
但我们没有变
But we're not.
我爱你
I love you.
这一点没有变
That's part of this.
是因为那个亚裔男孩吗
Is this about you and the Asian boy?
-你想让我  -不
- Do you want me to-- - No.
他叫格伦
His name is Glenn.
昨天有一个你认为病了的人想要杀死我
He saved my life yesterday when one of the people
他救了我
you think is sick tried to kill me.
这事够印象深刻吗
How's that for dramatic?
事情不是你想象的那样
Things aren't what you think they are.
不是的
They aren't.
不要赶他们走
Don't do this.
好吗  不是因为我和格伦
Okay? It's not about me and Glenn.
也不是因为我和你
It's not about me and you.
这全在于你
It's about you.
这关乎到你是一个什么样的人
It's about who you are,
你想要成为什么样的人
who you're gonna be.
赫谢尔
Hershel!
又出现了
It happened again.
她可能往南走了
...Also shows she could be moving this way south.
如果索菲亚一直顺着那个方向
If Sophia kept in that direction,
她很可能已经走出森林  进入农田了
she might have gotten out of the forest and into the farmland.
我们走74号公路去常春藤路
So we take 74 up to Ivy road,
然后下车步行往南
then push down south on foot
穿过森林  一直走到克里斯多夫
through the forest till we hit Christopher,
向东走几里  然后原路返回
go east a couple of miles and then double back.
-瑞克  -赫谢尔
- Rick. - Hershel.
我们需要带上枪去找索菲亚
We just have our guns out because we're gonna go look for Sophia.
在此之前  你可以帮我个忙
Before you do that, I could use your help with something.
算我一个
Count me in.
谢谢  但是我只需要瑞克
Thank you, but I just need Rick.
我去谷仓那边看着  好了来找我
I'll be down at the barn keeping watch until you're ready.
-我以为他死了  -肖恩  我不
- I thought he was dead. - Shane, I don't--
他回来的时候  就在那一刻
Then when he came back, right then, right there,
我希望他真的已经死了
you see I wished he was.
不是因为你不再属于我
Not-- not because you wouldn't be mine,
而是因为我知道早晚他都会死的
but because I knew that sooner or later he would be dead.
看看瑞克
See Rick,
他不适合这个世界
he ain't built for this world,
不适合现在这样的世界
not for what it is now.
你错了  你错了
You're wrong. You're wrong.
洛莉  他救过你几次
Lori, how many times has he saved your life?
我只想知道有几次  因为据我计算
I just-- I want to know how many times. Because by my count,
我在不同的情境下救过你四次
I've saved your life on four different occasions.
同时也算救了卡尔四次
And that's Carl's too.
所以我只想问你
So I just want to ask you,
瑞克救过你几次
how many times has Rick saved your life?
在营地的那晚
That night at the camp.
在营地  吃完烤鱼的那次
That night at the camp after the fish fry.
不不不  你看  不
No no no. See, no.
那次也是我救了你
That was me too.
瑞克来晚了
You see, Rick, he showed up late
因为他去做一件无意义  相当于自杀的事
because he went on a suicide mission over nothing.
是的  他去了
Yeah, he joined in,
如果他没有为了救一个毒贩
but see, we wouldn't have been in that situation
而丢下我们
if he hadn't left because he felt
我们就不会遭遇那种事
that he needed to leave to save a drug dealer.
我们失去了艾米  小吉
And so we lost Amy and we lost Jim.
还失去了...
We lost--
瑞克跟我说了
Rick told me.
说了什么
Told you what?
我知道你为什么不告诉我
And I know the reason why you didn't
因为你知道孩子是我的
is because you know it's mine.
-是瑞克的  -好吧
- It's Rick's. - Okay.
瑞克回来之前
You know, we carried on quite a bit
我们好过一阵  洛莉  孩子是我的  你知道
before rick got back, lori. It's mine. You know it is.
不是  你错了
You're wrong. You're wrong.
对不起  肖恩  对不起
I'm sorry. Shane, I'm sorry.
即便孩子是你的  也不会喊你爸爸
But even if it's yours, it's not gonna be yours.
永远不会
It's never gonne be yours
你做什么都无法改变这一点
and there's nothing you can do to change that.
我用不着改变
I don't need to.
等下  肖恩
Hey, Shane.
我能和你谈谈吗
Can I talk to you for a sec?
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
我知道你认为索菲亚已经死了
I know you think Sophia's dead
不用再继续找她
and that we should stop looking for her.
-可那纯属是放屁  -小伙子  注意用词
- But that's bullshit. - Hey, man, watch your mouth.
找到她之前  我们得一直留在这里
We're gonna stay here until we find her.
你觉得我们该这么办吗
You think that's what we should do?
据我所知  就得这么办
It's what I know we should do.
那我们就留下
Then we stay.
这样的话  我们就得
That means we got to do
想尽一切办法留下来
whatever we got to do to make that happen.
比如帮忙做杂活吗
Like help out with chores?
比如帮忙做杂活
Like help out with the chores.
卡尔
Carl.
过来一下
Come here for a minute.
要不你去看看能不能给你妈搭把手
Why don't you go see what your mom wants?
好吗  快去
Hmm? Go on.
卡尔
Hey, Carl.
别再让我听到你出言不逊
Don't let me hear you talk like that again.
怎么了
What's up?
他娘的
Son of a bitch.
你看到他去哪里了吗
You see where he went?
-谁  -别跟我来这套  行吗
- Who? - Don't even try to shit me, okay?
-什么意思  -戴尔  格伦
- What? - Dale, Glenn.
看到戴尔去哪里了吗
Did you see where Dale went?
看到了  他让我跑去给他拿些水
Yeah, he asked me to run and get him some water.
他说会帮我放会哨
He said he'd cover me on watch.
然后你回来的时候他就不见了
And he was gone when you got back, huh?
对
Yeah.
-他不会有事吧  -不会
- You think he's okay? - Oh, he's fine.
那他为什么还玩下声东击西?
Why'd he bail then?
这样你就没法给我指出他跑的方向了
So you wouldn't tell me which way he went.
我不懂
I don't get it.
对  伙计  你不懂
No, man, you don't.
底部的裂缝就像胶一样
The silt on the bottom is like glue.
你会沉下去
You just sink in.
那就是露·布什
That's Lou Bush.
你认识他
You knew him?
"露"是"露易丝"的简称
Lou as in louise.
她在路头那有家农场
She has a farm up the road.
种的大多是甜玉米
Sweet corn mostly.
周末在哈普曼的酒吧打工
Worked at Hapman's bar on weekends.
我不认识那个男的
The man, I don't know him,
但我认得那身工作服
but the coveralls,
我去过他工作的地方
I've been to where he worked.
你杀死过多少个
How many have you killed?
数不胜数
Too many to count.
能收手吗
Can you stop?
外面的那些人
There are people out there
大脑不受自己支配
who haven't been in their right minds,
但我相信他们能恢复正常
people who I believe can be restored.
你谈论的不是行尸  对吗
You're not talking about the walkers, are you?
你是否把他们当人看不重要
It doesn't matter if you see them as human beings anymore.
可如果你和你的人想留下
But if you and your people are going to stay here,
你们就得把他们当人看待
that's how you're gonna have to treat them.
我的农场  我的谷仓  我说了算
My farm, my barn, my say.
-看见没  -看见什么
- You see it? - See what?
我会找到她
I'll find her.
今天早上的事  我感到很抱歉
Hey, I'm sorry about what happened this morning.
你当时只是要去找她
You wanted to look for her.
为什么
Why?
我一直想问你
This whole time I've wanted to ask you.
因为我觉得她还活着
'cause I think she's still out there.
事实是  我还能做什么
Truth is, what else I got to do?
我们会找到她
We'll find her.
会的
We will.
我有预感
I see it.
奥蒂斯说如果你能拉着他们走一半路程
Otis said if you get them halfway out
剩下靠他们自己就能走完
they'll do the rest of the work.
他做过多少次
How many times did he do this?
一有晃悠到农场的
If one wandered onto the property,
奥蒂斯就会把他们弄进谷仓
Otis would get them into the barn.
现在我们得干这活了
Now we have to.
谷仓要是满了怎么办
What happens when the barn gets full?
-天哪  -抓住杆子
- Jeez! - Get the pole!
吉米  吉米  瑞克你抓住它
Jimmy. Jimmy. You got it.
慢点  慢点  引着他
Easy. Easy, Rick. Lead him.
吉米会帮我们看着
Jimmy will spot for us.
往前引  瑞克
Lead him lead him, rick.
诱饵是你  不是手里的杆子
You're the carrot, not the stick.
按我说的做  诱导着他
You heard me, just lead him.
他就会跟你走
He'll come to you.
你说奥蒂斯做起来很容易
You told me he handled them easily.
这还叫容易
This is easy?
比有些事容易
It's easier than some things.
来  走这边
Come on. Come on, over here.
玛姬
Maggie.
喂
Hey.
玛姬
Maggie.
玛姬  等一下下就好
Maggie, just stop for a second.
你问我这件事  你告诉戴尔  这都成
You talked about it. You told Dale, fine.
但我让你别说出去  我告诉过你了
I asked you. I told you.
我就求过你这一件事  一件事
I just asked you for one thing. One thing.
我做不到
I couldn't do it.
我爸现在要把你们赶走  他跟我说了
My dad's gonna kick you guys out now. He told me.
不  瑞克会想办法说服你爸
No, Rick's gonna work something out with your dad.
-我必须告诉他们  -你根本没必要说
- Okay? I had to tell them. - You did not.
不  我必须说
No, I did.
我自己想说出去
I wanted to.
听我说  我忘记了
Listen, you see I forgot.
我忘了  或者也是没多想
Okay? I forgot or I stopped thinking about it
也许我不愿意想这件事
Or maybe I didn't want to think about it.
我让他们把我吊进井里  觉得好玩
I let them lower me into that well like it was fun,
就像我在玩"传送门"
Like I was playing "Portal."
-这是个游戏  -当然是游戏
- It's a video game. - Of course it's a video game.
可是昨天在药房发生的事
And then the pharmacy
让我清醒过来
happened yesterday and I realized something.
我忘了他们很危险
I forgot that they're dangerous.
我不管他们是病人还是死人
I don't care if they're sick people or dead people,
反正他们很危险
they're dangerous.
而且我还意识到
And then I realized something else.
我不想你再有任何危险
That I don't want you in danger ever.
虽然我痛恨曝出你爸爸的秘密
So I hate to blow your dad's big secret,
但我讨厌保密
But I'm sick of secrets.
秘密会杀了你
Secrets get you killed.
所以我宁愿你活着恨我
And I'd rather have you pissed off at me and alive
也不想你死了爱我
Than liking me and dead.
这就是我告诉他们的原因
So that's why I told them.
喂  僵尸诱饵
Hey, walker bait.
别这么叫我
Don't call me that.
好吧  格兰
Okay, Glenn.
老头  这可真是个藏东西的好地方啊
Man, this is a good hiding place.
咱还没怎么来过沼泽  对吧
We ain't been in the swamps much, huh?
你怎么就不利用你的追踪技巧
Imagine if you applied your tracking skills
去找索菲亚呢
To finding Sophia.
要不
How about
你把那袋子给我  如何
You just give me that bag, huh?
我不会这么做的
I'm not gonna do that.
你会给我的  戴尔
Yeah you are, Dale.
除非嘛
Unless, well,
你能先一枪把我撂倒
You do have that rifle over your shoulder.
你想像对付奥蒂斯一样杀掉我吗
You gonna shoot me like you did Otis?
再编个故事
Tell another story?
不  老兄
No, man.
其实在阴暗的光线下
Hell, when you really look at it
这么看过去
In the cold light of day,
你已经跟死人差不多了
You're pretty much dead already.
把枪给我吧  快点儿
Just give me the guns. Do it now.
你觉得这样就能保证大家安全吗
You think this is gonna keep us safe?
对  我知道能
Mm-hmm. I know it is.
瑞克正在和赫谢尔谈
Rick is trying to get Hershel--
戴尔  闭嘴  别说了  把枪给我
Dale, shut up. Just shut up and give me the guns.
你非要我一枪毙了你吗
Am I gonna have to shoot you?
非要我杀了你吗  只有这么做才行吗
Do I have to kill you? Is that what it's gonna take?
是啊
Yeah.
只有这么做才行
That's what it's gonna take.
肖恩  你属于这里
This is where you belong, Shane.
怎么说  戴尔
How's that, Dale?
这个世界  如今的模样
This world, what it is now,
你这人就属于这世道
This is where you belong.
也许我没你这种生存的本事
And I may not have what it takes to last for long,
不过我无所谓
but that's okay.
因为至少我可以凭良心说
'Cause at least I can say
在这个世界陷入深渊时
when the world goes to shit
我没有和它一起堕落
I didn't let it take me down with it.
说得好
Fair enough.
你看起来都该去排队买特价早餐了
You look like you should be in line for the early bird special.
把你帽子拿来  我帮你洗洗  好吗
Go get your cap. I'll wash it for you, okay?
你们知道出什么事了吗
Do you know what's going on?
-大伙去哪儿了  -你们没看见瑞克吗
- Where is everyone? - You haven't seen Rick?
他跟赫谢尔出去了
He went off with Hershel.
我们几小时前就该出发了
We were supposed to leave a couple hours ago.
就是啊  搞什么鬼啊
Yeah you were. What the hell?
瑞克跟我们说他要出去一会儿
Rick told us he was going out.
搞毛啊  你们当这是开玩笑的对吧
Damn it. Isn't anybody taking this seriously?
我们又不是没线索
We got us a damn trail.
开始吧
Oh, here we go.
-这是什么  -你挺我吗  老弟
- What's all this? - You with me, man?
这就对了  该像个大人了
Yeah. Time to grow up.
-你拿好枪了吧  -拿好了  戴尔呢
- You already got yours? - Yeah. Where's Dale?
-他就来  -我以为咱们不能拿枪呢
- He's on his way. - Thought we couldn't carry.
我们能  而且必须这样
We can and we have to.
在我们认为这儿应该是个安全的地方时
Look, it was one thing sitting around here picking daisies
坐下来摘个菊花啥的倒没问题
When we thought this place was supposed to be safe.
可我们现在知道这儿不安全
But now we know it ain't.
你来吗  老弟  你要保护你女人吗
How about you, man? You gonna protect yours?
这就对了  你能开枪吗
That's it. Can you shoot?
你能消停会儿吗
Can you stop?
你把枪发给大家
You do this, you hand out these guns,
我爸今晚就会赶你们走
my dad will make you leave tonight.
-肖恩  我们必须留下  -这是怎么了
- We have to stay, Shane. - What is this?
我们哪儿也不去  懂吗
We ain't going anywhere, okay?
听好了  赫谢尔  他要明白
Now look, Hershel, he's just gotta understand.
懂吗  他必须明白
Okay? He-- well, he's gonna have to.
现在我们得找到索菲亚  我说的对吗
Now we need to find Sophia. Am I right?
对吧  现在我要你拿好这个
Huh? Now I want you to take this.
你拿好了  卡尔  你要保护妈妈
You take it, Carl, and you keep your mother safe.
无论做什么
You do whatever it takes.
你明白怎么做  拿好枪  然后动手吧
You know how. Go on, take the gun and do it.
瑞克说了不许拿枪  这轮不到你说话
Rick said no guns. This is not your call.
这事不由你说了算
This is not your decision to make.
我靠
Oh shit.
搞什么啊
What is that?
-搞什么啊  -肖恩
- What is that? - Shane!
你们这是搞什么鬼
What the hell are you doing?
-肖恩  退后  -你的人怎么都拿起枪了
- Shane, just back off. - Why do your people have guns?
你们开什么玩笑  看见没
Are you kidding me? You see?
你看见他们抓的玩意了吗
You see what they're holding onto?
-我知道我抓的是谁  -没  老头  你不懂
- I see who I'm holding onto. - No, man, you don't.
肖恩  让我们处理吧  待会儿再谈
Shane, just let us do this and then we can talk.
瑞克  你想谈什么
What you want to talk about, Rick?
这些东西不是病了  他们不是人
These things ain't sick. They're not people.
他们死了  别心疼他们了
They're dead. Ain't gonna feel nothing for them
因为他们只会杀人
'cause all they do, they kill!
这些怪物
These things right here,
就是杀死艾米的凶手
they're the things that killed amy.
他们杀了奥蒂斯  他们会把我们杀光
They killed Otis. They're gonna kill all of us.
肖恩  闭嘴
Shane, shut up!
赫谢尔  我问问你
Hey, Hershel man, let me ask you something.
一个活生生的人
Could a living breathing person,
面对这个能毫发无伤吗
could they walk away from this?
不
No!
-快住手  -胸口连中三枪
- Stop it! - That's three rounds in the chest.
一个活生生的人  能承受得了这个吗
Could someone who's alive, could they just take that?!
它怎么还好好的啊
Why is it still coming?
那是它的心脏  它的肺
That's its heart, its lungs.
它怎么还好好的啊
Why is it still coming?
-肖恩  够了  -是啊  老兄你说的对
- Shane, enough. - Yeah, you're right, man.
是够了
That is enough.
为了一个走丢的小女孩  我们已经冒够险了
Enough risking our lives for a little girl who's gone!
我们受够住在这满是杀人怪物的谷仓旁了
Enough living next to a barn full of things that are trying to kill us.
都够了  瑞克  今时不同往日
Enough. Rick, it ain't like it was before!
如果你们还想活着  还想活下去
Now if y'all want to live, if you want to survive,
你必须为它战斗
You got to fight for it!
我是说就在这儿战斗  就在此刻
I'm talking about fighting right here, right now.
抓着套杆
Take the snare pole.
赫谢尔  帮我抓着这套杆
Hershel, take the snare pole.
赫谢尔  听我的  求你了
Hershel, listen to me, man, please.
快抓着  赫谢尔
Take it now. Hershel!
抓着
Take it!
别  肖恩  别这样  兄弟  等等
No, shane. Do not do this, brother. Wait!
-别这样  -瑞克
- Don't do it! - Rick!
求你了
Please!
出来吧  出来吧  我们就在这儿
Come on. Come on, we're out here.
这样解决不了问题
This is not the way!
求你了
Please!
躲到我后边去
Get behind me.
来吧
Come on.
-玛姬  -去吧
- Maggie. - It's okay.
退后
Stay back!
住手
Stop!
索菲亚  索菲亚
Sophia? Sophia!
Sophia. Sophia.
不  索菲亚
Oh no. Sophia.
索菲亚
Sophia.
不
No.
索菲亚
Sophia.
别看
Don't watch.